Well, you may have never
been formally charged, doctor.
However, I have here
the sworn statement
alleging that, on occasion,
you have falsified
medical records.
You have withheld...
Cut to Camera 1.
Prescribed drugs... Camera 2.
From pharmacies which
you own, is that correct?
I refuse to sit here
and be subjected to
these unwarranted attacks
and innuendos.
One.
Well, I think the doctor's
gonna make a house call.
On our next program,
we will be looking
at the other side of the story.
Matte the font.
Until then, I'm Steve
Emerson. Good evening.
Limo to take you to
the airport is outside.
Beautiful.
You got my ticket?
Would I forget?
Network wants you in L.A. for
an affiliate's meeting next week.
Um, your producer
wants you to do a story
on vigilante groups
in Iowa. Iowa?
Says there's at least two.
Well, you tell Jack I said no.
I wanna do the piece
on juvenile prisons.
You're not going to Atlanta
to see Linda, are you?
I'll call you on
my return flight.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Atlanta, Georgia.
Thank you for
flying with Eastern.
Steve Emerson
for Linda Coolidge.
You...
Uh, Steve Emerson to
see you, Miss Coolidge.
Yes, ma'am.
You can go right up.
Sir.
I like your show
better than 60 Minutes.
I watch it all the time.
Thank you very much.
Hi, how are you? Oh.
Uh... Hey, little guy.
Ah.
Hello.
Welcome to Atlanta.
Ho-ho. Very good.
Let me see you.
Ooh. You look dashing as ever.
You said you wanted
to see me very badly.
Here I am.
So why don't you
come and sit down?
Cheers.
Steven,
I am on to something you
are going to find very exciting.
A very hot story.
I see.
Is there something
wrong with that? No.
I just thought maybe you just
wanted to see me, that's all.
No, I do.
But this is an important story.
The mob is wired to
the state government
at the highest level.
You got any proof?
A snitch.
How good?
Oh, I checked him
out. He's connected.
What's in it for you?
We share the story.
We share a story.
Uh-huh.
I don't think so.
Take a look at this from
my point of view for a minute.
We have a messy public divorce.
I get stuck as co-anchor
down here at a
local station in Atlanta
while you stay with the network.
You even have your own show.
Steven, I want out of here.
This is my way
back to the network.
Please.
Oh, you know
you'll never change.
Okay.
Ah. Good.
Well, when do I
meet this snitch?
Tonight.
I figure we can hear the
yelling and shouting from here.
Stand up and put both
your hands on the poles.
Why should I?
I gotta make sure
you're not wired.
Okay, here's the deal.
I want $50,000 and your
promise of strict confidentiality.
I'll call you tomorrow
to find out if it's a sale.
Whoa, wait a... Wait a minute.
I don't even know who you are.
I've gotta have your
word you'll protect me.
Don't worry.
If you don't, I'm a dead man.
You've got my word.
Okay.
The name's Billy Ray Webber.
You can check me out.
Linda already checked you out.
She didn't give up your
name and neither will I.
Now, how good's
the stuff you've got?
I'm gonna show you the paperwork
that'll not only put some
top state government people
out of business, but a big
mob boss is gonna do time.
I'll check with New
York on the money
on two conditions.
Number one: if I don't like
what you've got, the deal is off...
Hey.
- -and second:
the next time I meet
you, it's on my turf.
I'll call you.
Mr. Emerson, can
you tell us anything...?
Can you tell us anything about
Linda Coolidge's condition?
What are you talking about?
Somebody shot Linda Coolidge
at her apartment this evening.
Ah, Mr. Emerson?
Mr. Emerson?
Mr... Mr. Steve Emerson?
That's right.
I'm Lieutenant
Daniels of Homicide.
I'm sorry about
Miss Coolidge, sir.
What happened?
Well, a neighbor reported
hearing a loud fight,
and then a gunshot at 10:15.
May I see you back
here for a second, sir?
The security guard was
notified, and he found her.
And she was dead by the
time the, uh, paramedics arrived.
Mr. Emerson.
I've notified Linda's family.
All right, I'll call you if
I need anything else.
What's he doing here?
Do I know you?
No. But we know you, don't we?
Who was that?
Paul Lockwood.
Businessman. Her fiancé.
Steve, what happened?
Uh, beg your pardon, sir.
I'm Lieutenant Daniels,
Homicide. Who are you?
I'm Les McCall. I own WHN.
And this is Nelson White.
Now, somebody
said she'd been shot.
How is she?
Miss Coolidge died
about 30 minutes ago.
Oh, no.
Mr. Emerson, you
probably don't remember,
but we met last year
at an NAB luncheon.
Anyway, I'm... I-I'm very sorry.
We all loved her.
I-I-I mean, Nelson here was...
Was Linda's
co-anchor at my station.
Any idea who did it?
Not yet. Uh, but
I'm sorry, gentlemen.
There's work to be done
here, so if you'll excuse me.
Let me know if there's
anything we can do.
Anything at all.
And, Steve...
Steve, give me a call.
You got any leads?
Not yet.
Any witnesses?
None.
I don't understand.
It's a security building.
How could anyone get
access into her apartment?
I don't know, but I was
thinking, Mr. Emerson,
that perhaps you could help
me with a couple of details.
Sure, like what?
According to the
security guard's log,
you entered the building
at 9:15 this evening.
That's right. So what?
There's no record
of you leaving.
That's because when
I went downstairs,
there were photographers
at the entrance,
so I slipped out the side door.
But the security guard reported
the only time he left his desk
was when the neighbor
reported the gunshot.
And he came up
to this apartment.
Well, he's lying.
When I went back down to
the lobby, he wasn't at his desk.
He certainly wouldn't
have been there
if you left after the
gunshot was fired.
Let me tell you something.
You better get some hard proof
before you make
any more accusations.
'Cause I don't think you
know who you're dealing with.
Mr. Emerson.
What?
Can you account
for your whereabouts
during the time of the
murder at 10:15 this evening?
You're damn right I
can. I was with someone.
Who, Mr. Emerson?
It was a privileged
communication
with a news source.
I can't tell you.
Well, if I were you, sir, I
would certainly want an alibi.
If I told you, I would be...
placing my source
in serious jeopardy.
I won't do that.
One moment, sir.
Mr. Emerson,
do you recognize that gun, sir?
It's my gun.
It was my gun. I gave it
to Linda some time ago.
Why did you give it to her?
We had a very
messy public divorce.
There are a lot of
crazies running around.
I was concerned
about her safety.
Well, I'm gonna run that gun
through ballistics
tests tonight,
because it's been
recently fired.
Do you have an attorney, sir?
Why, you placing
me under arrest?
Mr. Emerson, one of my
men just found this gun
in your car, sir.
Morning, ladies.
Good morning, ladies.
Good morning. You're all
looking well this morning.
Easy.
Easy does it, now.
Look at this as part
of life's food chain.
All right, look at
it as my breakfast.
Police arrested
Emerson late last night,
and he was released on
$500,000 bail this morning.
Emerson was
unavailable for comment.
Updating the national
news: in Washington today,
with major pieces of business
left on the senate's calendar,
the leadership was
faced with a choice
of either
postponing this bill...
Hello?
I don't know how it
is there in Atlanta,
but here in Willow
Springs the sun's shining,
children are
playing in the creek
and honest folk are
getting ready to go to work.
Sometimes I wish
I was an orphan.
I said, honest folk are
getting ready to go to work.
Okay, okay, okay. Heh.
So, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury,
the people's evidence
has overwhelmingly shown
that this defendant also had
a motive to kill the decedent
and had full access
to his warehouse.
These facts, beyond
a reasonable doubt,
compel you to deliver a verdict
of guilty of murder
in the first degree.
Thank you.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Mr. Matlock.
Members of the jury,
I know we'd all like
to get out of here
and go someplace where the
air conditioning actually works,
so I'm gonna be brief.
Now, I've got to be fair
and recognize, as do you,
that the prosecution
has collected
a lot of circumstantial
evidence.
But the problem is,
it is all circumstantial.
Now, they've accused
this man of murder.
But no one saw the crime occur.
No body has ever been found.
No one knows how the
victim died, or if he died at all.
In fact, they have never proved
a crime was actually committed.
And now, I'm gonna count to ten.
And when I'm done,
this supposed victim's
gonna walk through
that door over there.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Ten.
So you see, members of the jury,
in fairness, you must
return a verdict of not guilty.
Each and every one of
you was staring at that door
because you had
a reasonable doubt
that a crime was even committed.
And you must let
this man go free.
He was staring at that
door as hard as you were.
And so were they.
Your Honor, the law is
quite clear on tenants' rights,
and I respectfully ask
you to order the landlord
to return my client's
security deposit
in the amount of $750.
Thank you, counselor.
If there's nothing further,
I will take the matter
under submission.
We'll receive his decision
by mail in a couple of weeks.
I'll let you know.
I'll tell you the thing
about Clarence.
When you left his stand,
you knew you'd
gotten a shoeshine.
I mean, the man was an artist.
Yep. They don't make
'em like him anymore.
No. And I for one
am gonna miss him.
Hi. Hi.
Morning. Morning, Bert.
See you, Bert. See you.
How'd it go?
I got an acquittal.
Jury wasn't out long.
Well, justice was
swift this morning.
Let me ask you something. What?
Did it ever occur to
you that we could be
the best father and daughter
team to try a criminal case
here in Atlanta?
No, it didn't.
Hi, Phil. PHIL: Hi, Charlene.
Which is my way of
saying, I think that I'm ready
for a little more
challenging litigation.
Charlene, you've only
been out of law school
one year. Two.
Well. Hi, John.
Hi. And where am I gonna get
better on-the-job
training than with you,
Dad? Hm.
Hey, Wayne, you
are looking good.
Who are all these fellas?
Lawyers.
Stay away from lawyers.
They have ethics, no morals.
Yeah, but they sure do have fun.
Where'd you meet 'em?
Met most of 'em at Santino's.
That's a pickup bar, isn't it?
No.
It's where we
yuppies go to unwind.
Haven't you ever seen
a beer commercial?
Hmph.
Bob, how's that new car running?
Running good, Ben.
Good-looking car.
Paid way too much for it.
Harvey Ravanelle's
looking for you, Ben.
What's an important
lawyer like Harvey Ravanelle
want with the likes of me?
Morning, Hazel.
Hi, Hazel. HAZEL: Hi.
Phones messages
are on your desk,
Charlene's lunch date
has been cancelled,
Mr. and Mrs. Pearson
are in your office,
and you forgot to
file your tax form.
Damn. I filed it for you.
Hazel, sometime let's
you and me get married.
Get a new suit
and I'll think about it.
I'm sorry to keep
you folks waiting.
Charlene, this is Mark
and Betty Pearson.
Mark has milk cattle
over at Willow Springs.
This is my associate and my
daughter. What can I do for you?
Old man Cornell
said my dog bit him.
Says he's gonna sue us in court.
Is that a fact?
Well, we've got four
lines of defenses.
One: my dog doesn't bite.
Two: my dog was
tied up at the time.
Three: I don't think
you really got bit.
Four: I don't have a dog.
My dog don't bite.
Yes, ma'am.
Really?
I'll be right with him.
If you'll just go with
my associate here,
she'll draft a
strongly worded letter
to disabuse Mr. Cornell
of this fruitless litigation.
Is it gonna be expensive?
Well, her time is
not as dear as mine.
So it's gonna cost you $15.
That's 10 for the letter and
5 for a leash for you dog.
And then I am taking
you out to lunch
so we can discuss our future.
I plan on being unavailable.
Harvey!
Sorry to drop in on
you like this, Benny.
Aw, it's a real honor,
your coming all the way
down from your penthouse.
I'm Ben Matlock. Steve Emerson.
Oh, I know my
mother's gonna be green
when she hears I met you.
Ben, our firm represents
Steve's network in this state,
but as you probably know,
Steve here needs a
top defense attorney.
It's all anybody
could talk about
down at the courthouse this
morning. Sit down, Mr. Emerson.
Know any of the details, Ben?
Friend of mine in the
DA's office told me about it.
Help yourself to peanuts.
I got 'em in barter from
a client down in Plains.
It's not who you think.
Look, Harvey, with all
due respect to Mr. Matlock,
I have some very close
friends in New York,
and they're excellent
defense attorneys.
I wouldn't do
that if I were you.
Why is that?
Well, let me explain
some of your problems.
First off, you got the
disposition of the jury
to consider.
They look at you as a
fast-talking TV personality
from New York.
And you're rich.
I'm hardly rich.
According to the standards of
folks around here, you're rich.
And you got another first strike
against you: you're an outsider.
You need a local boy,
somebody who's good.
Steve,
Ben here has a
record in criminal cases
probably second to none.
He's handled murder
trials all over the country.
Harvey, don't...
Don't press the man.
Harvey, I'm in
deep trouble here.
If I were in your
spot, I'd want Ben.
Wait a minute.
I said you need
somebody like me.
I didn't say I'd take the case.
What?
Your situation doesn't
sound too good to me.
Ben, we need you.
Harvey, I've got my
reputation to consider.
Money is no object here.
Money never is.
How much cash you got?
About 50,000. Any
bonds? Securities?
Another 50.
That'll do as a retainer.
A retainer?
Look, at it this way, Steve.
If I win, it'll be worth it.
If I don't, they take you
to the Georgia Diagnostic
and Classification Center
over near Jackson and
they electrocute you.
I think you made
your point, okay?
Harvey,
thanks for throwing
some business my way.
I appreciate it.
I'll talk to you later, Steve.
We got a lot of talking to do.
You gotta tell me everything
that happened that night,
anything important
I should know.
Well, my marriage
to Linda was stormy.
The divorce was even worse.
But I loved her.
I didn't kill her.
I understand you've got an
alibi for the time of the murder.
That's a privileged
news communication.
I can't reveal the source.
Even if it means your own neck?
I gave the man my word.
I don't have to tell you this
is gonna be an uphill battle.
Prosecution has all the cards.
I'll give it the
best shot I got.
Next to injustice,
I hate losing.
Thank you.
Ben, Hazel said you wanted
me here for the arraignment.
This is Steve Emerson.
My daughter, Charlene, will
be associate counsel on this.
How do you do?
I am so pleased to be working
on your case, Mr. Emerson.
I'm delighted also.
You're Ben Matlock, right?
Yes, sir. I've heard
a lot about you.
Burton Hawkins. I'll be
prosecuting this case.
Can we talk, please?
First of all, I don't wanna
cut any deals on this one.
I'm asking for murder one.
What else? "Else"?!
What are you...?
You said, "First of all."
What's second?
Aha.
How soon can we try this case?
Soon as you like.
"People of the State of
Georgia v. Steve Emerson."
Case number F81-500.
Benjamin Matlock for
the defense, Your Honor.
All right. MATLOCK:
Defendant is present.
He's been informed
of his constitutional
and statutory rights,
received a copy
of the indictment,
waives further reading thereof.
Defendant pleads
not guilty, Your Honor,
requests a jury trial.
The time is waived.
What about, uh, September 16th?
Fine with my client.
Prosecution agrees.
All right, this case is set
for trial on September 16th,
Courtroom 203 of the Criminal
Division of Superior Court,
9 a.m.
Mr. Emerson, is it true you're
protecting a news source?
Why were you here in Atlanta?
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I can only answer
one question at a time.
Mr. Emerson has no comment.
What's your strategy?
Did he have an alibi?
Hold it, hold it.
All I'll say is,
the State has seen fit to assign
their most brilliant prosecutor,
Burton Hawkins, to this trial.
Now, they don't assign a
man like "Death Row" Hawkins
unless they feel they got a
lot of problems with their case.
And they may have
a couple of problems
they don't know about yet.
That's all. Thank you.
They're your batteries,
boys. That's all.
Step into my office. Come on.
Now, this is important.
I don't want you making
any statements to the press.
Absolutely none. Why is that?
I don't want this
case tried on TV
before we get it
in the courtroom.
All right. What about
this prosecutor?
How good is he? I don't
know much about him.
He's sorta new. But
he must be good,
or he wouldn't be on this case.
Oh, he's good. He's got
a great conviction rate.
DA's office thinks
that he's a real comer.
It's all right. She's a lawyer.
What happens now?
I spoke with a friend of
mine who should know.
And he hasn't heard
anything about the syndicate
being involved in
state government.
So I've gotta find the
man you were with
the night of the
murder, and fast.
Charlene here's gonna check out
the other people in
Miss Coolidge's life,
see who might have had a motive.
That's something I'd
like to work on myself.
I want you to stay in your hotel
room and shut off the phone.
Wait a minute. I'm an
investigative reporter.
I'm not gonna sit
in a hotel room.
Right now what you are
is a reporter facing
the electric chair.
Now, you'll do as I say,
or I won't represent you.
It's as simple as that.
Okay.
I'll be at the hotel.
Ben.
Thanks.
Let's earn our money.
Okay.
Um, it's okay. I'm a lawyer.
What say, Tyler, a little lunch?
Absolutely.
Ben, take my advice
and stay away from
the commodities market.
I hear there's a big
soybean crop coming.
What's the difference? I
don't have the cash anyway.
You know, that's a
real shame, Tyler.
I know how bad you
wanna go to California,
live that easy life.
All those fine-looking
clothes, beautiful women,
fancy food with
the avocados in it.
You could sure do
yourself some good
selling soybean short.
I might be able to
invest you a little money.
Now, see, I knew that this
lunch was not about lunch.
Now, Ben, you got me out
of some serious trouble once
and I will be
eternally grateful.
Look in my eye.
You see the gratitude there?
But I am not doing any more
private investigative work.
Tyler, all I wanted to do is
advance you a little money.
I'm not doing any more PI work.
I happen to have
a check right here.
I'm out of that game.
See the check?
What's the case?
Linda Coolidge
was laid to rest today
in her hometown
of Utica, New York.
There were no services,
and only her mother and her
sister were at the gravesite,
which is the way Linda
would have wanted it.
She was, at heart, a
very private person.
It's hard to believe she's gone.
We'll be right back with
Dr. Farnsworth and the weather,
and Bill Tucker
with sports after this.
Touching tribute.
You didn't like her?
Oh, I did. But he didn't.
Ultimately.
Excuse me.
Mr. White? Yes?
Hi, I'm Charlene Matlock.
Our firm is handling
Steve Emerson's defense.
I was wondering if I could
ask you a few questions
about Linda Coolidge.
Is there somewhere
we could go talk?
I-I'm very sorry. I...
I don't have time right now.
Could I make an appointment?
Look, I'm sorry, but
my attorney told me
not to get involved with this.
Besides,
I don't know anything
about Linda's personal life.
Sorry.
It's Steve Emerson down
in Atlanta. Is Jimmy in?
Jimmy, I need you to express
me Linda's banking records
first thing in the
morning, okay?
Now, look, spare
me the legalities.
You've been our accountant
what? Eight, nine years?
Well, you'll stay my accountant
if you give me
those computer runs.
What are you doing here?
Same thing you're doing,
only I'm supposed to be here.
Phil.
Listen, I need all the clips
out of Research
you have on Linda.
Particularly anything
out of Atlanta,
with a heavy underline
on the social stuff.
I'm gonna call you back
tomorrow, okay? Thanks.
Ben isn't gonna like this.
Well, Ben isn't gonna
be electrocuted, is he?
Steve, I, uh...
I got those tapes up
you wanted to see.
Great.
You coming?
Oh, yeah.
You wanna run that tape, please?
Roll the A machine, please.
What are you looking for?
A clue to whoever
put that gun in my car.
Oh, listen, I, uh,
ordered up some additional
footage from WPKS.
What have you got?
Her boyfriend. Uh,
uh, what's his name?
Lockwood. Lockwood. Yeah, yeah.
Well, he claims he
was at a fundraiser.
Let's see if he's
telling the truth.
Roll the B machine, please.
You suspect Lockwood?
Hey, listen, at this point
I suspect everybody.
He told the police he
never left the ballroom.
Well, looks like his
alibi is better than mine.
Yeah.
Okay, listen, Steve,
if you need anything,
let me know, huh?
Morris, switch
back to the first tape.
Roll the A machine
again, please.
You might wanna find out
where her fellow
anchorman was that night.
Nelson White?
And what about helpful McCall?
Why is he sticking
his neck out for you?
Maybe he thinks
I'm a terrific guy.
I already asked him. He
said he was home, alone.
Thought he was married.
Separated. Where do you want
to have dinner tomorrow night?
I didn't know that we were
having dinner together
tomorrow night.
I thought you wanted a
full background on Linda.
I do.
Have dinner in my hotel
dining room around 8.
It's for you.
I'll take that in
Linda's dressing room.
Gonna tell Daddy on me?
Absolutely.
Which one of you
is the toughest?
What's it to you?
Here's a ten spot.
I come out and my car
hasn't been touched,
there'll be another
one just like it.
You got it.
♪ You always took The last ♪
♪ Of my pride ♪
♪ I realized ♪
♪ You hate goodbye ♪
Yeah?
Ben, now this is
exactly the reason
why I don't like
investigative work.
Take a look around here.
One: this is the kind of place
where you can catch
death like a cold.
And I assume there's a
powerful reason why we're here.
Two:
you never know when
one of these yahoos
is gonna get it in his
skull to mess with you.
Tyler, why are we here?
All right.
I put the word out
to some people
that we are looking for
a very special songbird.
I got a message on
my answering machine
that said if we came
here, we'd meet somebody.
You think the person we're
looking for could be here now?
Well, either that,
or they sent someone
to scout us out first.
You girls lost?
You see what I
mean? It never fails.
I asked you a question, Leroy.
Of course you realize
that because of this scholar,
we have blown our meeting.
No one's gonna talk to us now.
Let's you and me get it on, son.
You know, friend? You're
right. You made your point.
We're leaving. Excuse us.
You ain't going...
Damn, I hate this business.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you have just seen
a demonstration
of what can be done
if you're accosted
as my friend here was.
But what if you're
not an ex-Marine?
What if you're the one
to suffer bodily harm?
The smartest thing you
can do is come to see me.
Benjamin Matlock, fully
licensed attorney at law.
Your personal injuries
can be worth big money.
Night, all.
♪ You hate goodbye ♪
Well, as far as Linda's
co-workers are concerned,
I think that we should take a
closer look at McCall and White.
Why don't you nose
around the TV station?
The weatherman loves to talk.
Hm. The last time I
listened to that sucker
I got rained on at the beach.
I'll see you all in the morning.
Where's Emerson?
He was at the TV station
yesterday afternoon.
Doing what? Some investigating.
I told him to stay out of sight.
Well, actually,
I was rather impressed
with what he was doing.
He was getting Linda's
financial records,
going over news footage
of the murder scene.
You were?
Were what?
Impressed?
Yes, I was.
Were you impressed when
I told him stay at his hotel?
Did you consider I might
have had a reason for that?
Well, he was getting results.
I saw no point in stopping him.
Charlene, one of the reasons
I charge my clients
so much money
is so they'll do
what I tell 'em.
This man is a
target for the press.
We can get that
same information.
When are you seeing him again?
We're meeting in the dining room
at his hotel tonight
so I can get some
background on Linda Coolidge.
You find him attractive.
So does most of America.
You're his lawyer.
Are you insinuating
that I might let any
personal feelings
I have about a client
interfere with my
professional relationship?
I haven't said anything.
Yet.
Good.
Any luck getting in to
see the boyfriend? Um...?
Lockwood. Yeah.
No. He wouldn't
return my phone calls.
So I... made an appointment
under another name.
That's very devious.
Yes, I thought
you might approve.
I'll see you later. Yeah.
Yes, ma'am?
Put him on.
Speaking.
I'll meet you anywhere you say.
Right. I'll be there.
This is ridiculous.
How can they
treat you like that?
Beg pardon? I'm amazed.
You are?
I am astounded that a
scientist of your stature
is forced to dress like that.
What, do they want you
to look like good weather?
Who are you?
I'm Tyler Hudson,
Dr. Farnsworth.
I've been a fan of yours
since you were on radio,
doing forecasts out
there at the airport.
I never missed your show.
If I don't go along,
they'll get some kid
in here to replace me.
Mm. Uh, you work here?
No, no. I work for
a couple of lawyers.
But look, I am such a fan.
Could I buy you a cup of coffee?
I saw this fantastic
little sidewalk cafe
around the corner.
It would be great.
If it doesn't rain.
Trust me.
For old time's sake.
Mr. Lockwood.
Mr. Lockwood?
Yes?
Uh, you have a 2:00
appointment with Miss Henderson.
Oh, yes.
Well, that's me.
Actually, I'm Charlene Matlock.
I'm sorry about the deception,
but you wouldn't
return my phone calls.
If you think for one moment
that I'm gonna help the man
who killed my
fiancée, you're crazy.
Mr. Lockwood, uh,
I-I know how upset you must be.
Upset? We were to be
married in three weeks.
W-wouldn't you like to
be certain who killed her?
You're telling me
that Emerson didn't?
That's right, I am.
Now I know it's our
job to defend him,
but I happen to think
that he's innocent.
And wouldn't you
like to be certain
that the right man is convicted?
Isn't that important to you?
I really don't see how
I can be of any help.
Maybe you can't.
But what if you know something?
Something that you
may think is insignificant,
that might help us find
out who really did kill her?
You really believe
him, don't you?
Yes, I do.
Well, I'm sorry to hear that,
because Linda told
me all about him
and I think he's
going to be convicted
because he killed her.
Excuse me.
You got the time?
Twenty-five after 3.
This is your
business card, isn't it?
That it is.
I was about to give up on you.
Well, I had to make
sure you were alone.
Well, you're
right to be careful.
Your friend must be real nervous
considering what happened.
Afraid now Emerson will
talk to save his own skin.
Will he?
It's hard to say.
But with all these
newspeople chasing this story
somebody could find
out about your friend.
He'd be left hung out to dry.
Can you do anything for him?
Maybe.
Like what?
Tell him to call me tonight.
I'll have a proposition for him.
I'll tell him.
Hi. Hi. Sorry I'm late.
It's okay.
You look great.
Thank you.
A cocktail, ma'am?
Um, any diet drink.
I have no style.
Or maybe I have too much style.
I guess it all depends
on your point of view.
What is your point of view?
About what?
Me.
Well, we're not
supposed to be concerned
with your innocence or guilt.
But I think you're innocent.
What about your father?
My father.
My father would not say,
no matter what he thought.
Well, he really works that
simple country-boy routine, huh?
Well, he is a country boy.
He's just not simple.
Uh, we're from the
National Informer.
Come on, get out of here.
Do you usually have candlelit
dinners with your attorneys?
Look, get lost, okay?
Are you and Miss Matlock
something of an item here?
Steve, come on.
Come on, come on.
Come on, let's go.
Mr. Hawkins, what can you
tell us about the Emerson case?
Well, naturally,
Nelson, I can't discuss
any of the issues that
might be prejudicial.
But I do think that it raises
questions about the media.
- How's that?
- Well, for one thing...
Hello.
Ahem. Well, Mama,
I-I hope nothing's wrong,
'cause I can't come by tonight.
Well, I'm working real hard
trying to keep Steve
Emerson out of prison.
Charlene's working hard too.
She's doing a good job.
All right. You get a
good night's sleep now.
Night, Mama.
Okay.
What's that?
Bologna sandwich.
Chicken bologna.
Taste like bologna?
Less fat.
Hm.
Uh, why don't you have
someone shine your shoes?
Ever since Clarence down
at the courthouse retired
and his cousin took over,
I have been unable
to find acceptable
shoe maintenance.
See, he... He didn't
get in there too good.
Any time I go in the courtroom,
first thing the jury
looks at is my hair,
my suit and right in there.
Matlock and Matlock.
Yes, he is. Who's
calling, please?
Oh, well, one moment.
Very mysterious. Says
you're expecting him.
Hm.
I'm Ben Matlock.
Yes.
I'll be there.
Well, who was that?
Steve Emerson's alibi.
I'm Ben Matlock.
No kidding.
Here, Mary Beth.
Have a nice trip.
Where are you going?
Far away.
You have a proposition for me?
You testify you were
with Emerson that night.
I spoke to a couple
of the federal boys.
They'll put you in the
witness protection program.
Well, what's in it for them?
You tell them what you
were gonna tell Emerson.
Well, what about the money?
Doesn't look like you need it.
I just run this place
for some people.
What about the $50,000?
Too late for that.
Well, I don't like it.
I don't blame you.
But if I were in your position,
I'd take the best deal
I can get. This is it.
Okay.
Be at my office 10:00
tomorrow morning.
I'll have the
federal boys there.
♪ You can't run Run away ♪
♪ You can't run away ♪
♪ You can't hide Hide away ♪
♪ You can't hide away ♪
♪ You can't go find a way ♪
♪ You can't find a way ♪
♪ You can't run ♪
♪ It's time to go ♪
♪ You can't run away ♪
♪ And we both know ♪
♪ You cannot ♪
♪ Run ♪
♪ Run, run ♪
♪ I'm gonna, I'm
gonna I'm gonna ♪
♪ I'm gonna get you ♪
♪ Run, run ♪
♪ I'm gonna, I'm
gonna I'm gonna ♪
♪ I'm gonna get you ♪
♪ Run ♪
What the hell is going on here?
A man's been shot over there.
He's dead.
Heard you wanna read
that before you sign it?
It's a habit of
mine, lieutenant.
You know, I can't
understand something.
You were with some
hood in an nightclub at night
and you have no
idea who iced him?
If I had a glimmer,
I'd share it with you.
It could only help my client.
The death of this man Webber
is very bad news for our side.
You know, I've heard
about you, Matlock.
And if you're suppressing
evidence, I will nail you.
You can't have heard much.
You'd know I
don't break the law.
I leave that to
criminals and the police.
The police.
Your daughter?
Oh, yeah.
You must be proud.
You know, when she was 16
she ran off and
married some bum.
He went to jail,
she got pregnant.
The other day I calculated
I have represented
over 400 criminal cases.
People's very lives in my hands.
And I never felt so
much responsibility
as trying to raise
my daughter alone.
Always afraid I was
doing the wrong thing.
You know, sometimes no
matter what you do, you...
You just can't win.
Maybe.
Good night, lieutenant.
Very pretty.
Mr. Matlock?
That's right. Come
with us, please.
Why should I do that?
Let's keep this
polite, shall we?
As a matter of practice,
I like to know where I'm
going and who I'm going with.
By all means.
This way, please.
Take the blindfold off.
Ben Matlock, I'm Ernie Marzell.
I recognize you from
your photographs.
Sorry to invite you
here in this fashion
but it's something
of an emergency.
You're in no danger, and
you can leave after we talk.
What's the emergency?
The untimely death
of Billy Ray Webber.
What about it?
Billy Ray was my trusted friend.
I'm very distressed
by his murder.
I didn't see who did it.
Perhaps there's some detail.
Anything to give us some clue
to the identity of his killer.
I'm afraid I didn't
see much of anything.
It was very dark.
It's important that I
know who is responsible.
I was meeting with Billy Ray
to discuss a story
he had for sale.
About organized crime getting
involved with the state house.
What are you saying?
Billy Ray was a snitch?
That's one way to put it.
That's very upsetting news.
If it's news to you,
I suspect whoever
killed Linda Coolidge
did in Billy Ray.
What do you mean?
That newsman? Emerson?
No, Billy Ray was his alibi.
He wouldn't kill him.
But someone who was part
of Webber's story could have.
Naturally I know very little
about state government.
Nothing about organized crime.
You've led a sheltered life.
My father was a tailor.
Before I told my friends
to call me Ernie
"The Tailor" Marzell.
Whenever I'm aggravated,
nothing makes me feel better
than to hem a pair of pants.
Personally I prefer
to shine my shoes.
You don't know of a
good shoeshine stand
anywhere around town, do you?
I only wear suede.
That's a thought.
Well, I guess I'll be going.
Mr. Matlock, I understand
that you're a very
fine defense attorney.
How is it that we've
never had any business?
I don't know. Just
lucky, I guess.
Take Mr. Matlock
back to his car.
You all right?
I suppose.
You've been awfully quiet.
I guess tonight
reminded me of those
last few months with Linda.
All the paparazzi.
I'm sorry I lost my temper.
It's all right. No,
it's not all right.
I'm used to taking the heat.
I guess this just affected
me more than I realized.
You're only human.
One day I'm a hotshot
TV news correspondent.
Next day I'm on
trial for murder,
already convicted in the
press and my life is on hold.
Film at 11.
You are doing the smart thing.
You're taking action.
I admire you for that.
You know, you're terrific.
I have to go.
You really have to go?
It's a big day tomorrow.
Ben does like to start early.
Well, good night.
Good night.
Thanks again.
Yeah.
Uh, ha.
I really do have to go.
Bye.
Good night.
Well, this is just perfect.
Why in the hell didn't he shoot
somebody while he was at it?
You really can't blame
him, Ben. They're vultures.
Charlene, this paper's gonna
be in every checkout line
in every supermarket
in this city.
Do you know how
many prospective jurors
are gonna see this? All of 'em.
The Informer is gonna
print whatever it wants
whether it's true or not.
You mean like: "The two of 'em
were entwined in
intimate conversation"?
Just what are you suggesting?
I'm suggesting you
used very poor judgment
going up to his room
after what happened.
What if they'd photographed
you coming out of there?
Are you worried about
his reputation or mine?
Just how involved are you?
Are you asking as
a lawyer or a father?
Both.
Well, the answer to both of you
is that I resent the question.
That's not an answer.
Oh, yes it is.
Yes?
Send him in.
Our favorite client.
I was just reading about you.
What's all this about you
and Billy Ray Webber?
I just saw it on the news.
He's the guy I was with
the night Linda was killed.
What happened? He's dead.
And the mob didn't do it. I
was talking with one of 'em.
They're as anxious to find
out who did it as we are.
Well, what do we do now?
I'll tell you what you do now.
You give me your
word you'll do as I say,
when I say it, or get
yourself another lawyer.
All right, you've got it.
Jury selection starts
Monday. We have no alibi,
and no way to establish
reasonable doubt.
What we need is a
bright idea, and soon.
Good morning, people.
And have I got some
hot news for you.
We are in the
market for hot news.
Yeah, well here it is.
Now, maybe no one
listens to the weatherman.
But the weatherman sure
listens to everyone else.
Seems our Linda Coolidge
was one very ambitious lady.
Now, I hate to say it, pal,
but her apartment
had a swinging door.
She had two rejected lovers
on the staff with
motives for murder:
McCall and White.
You got any proof?
No.
But evidently there was
some type of red leather diary?
Yeah.
It was about so big.
She wrote everything in it.
Her ideas, her appointments.
She never went
anywhere without it.
Did you see it the
night of the murder?
Yeah, it was on
her coffee table.
Well, it's not there now,
and the police don't have it.
Well, if it was
there when you left,
and gone by the time
the police got there,
the murderer
might have taken it.
Leaves us nowhere.
Not necessarily.
I think I just got
a bright idea.
You reside in Atlanta,
and you are an
accountant, is that correct?
That's right, sir.
We are endeavoring
to impanel a jury
to try an indictment
against Steve Emerson.
That indictment charges him
with the murder
of Linda Coolidge.
Have you read anything
about this in the paper?
Or have you heard
anything about it
over the various news media?
Oh, yes.
Take a look at this.
I see. Mr. Cooper...
What do you think?
Terrific.
Go to it. But watch your step.
Or any conscientious scruples
which would prevent you
from returning a verdict
which would make it
mandatory upon the court
to impose the death sentence?
No, sir.
Thank you.
Mr. Matlock, your witness.
Mr. Cooper,
we didn't get you up too early
to come down here, did we?
No, I'm an early riser.
Yeah, me too.
Gives me a chance
to read the papers
and look at the news on TV.
Is that the same
for you? Oh, yes.
Yeah.
You were telling Mr. Hawkins
that, uh, you read something
about this case in the paper.
Are you a regular
subscriber to any newspaper?
We get the Atlanta Constitution.
Uh, we get the News.
We get the Weekly Courier.
And so I take it
from time to time
you've read something about
this case in those papers.
Oh, that's right.
Does your wife ever bring
home the National Informer?
Oh. Heh. Sometimes.
Yeah.
What do you think about
these papers and the TV news?
You think they've done a
reliable job covering this case?
I'd say so.
You tend to believe it.
Yes.
Did you see last
week's Informer?
The one with the
headline that said,
"Psychic Says Emerson
Killed Coolidge."
Yes. Uh...
Uh... Your Honor,
we have a real problem here.
If, uh, Mr. Cooper
read that article
and believes what he read,
then he can hardly be
considered impartial.
Now, on that ground, I
have no choice but to request
that he be excused for cause.
You're excused for
cause, Mr. Cooper.
Go the the second floor, please.
They call it, ahem,
selecting the jury.
You don't select the jury.
You kick off the ones
you really don't want
and what's left is the jury.
Any luck tying Ernie
Marzell into this case?
Not yet.
Well, if... If he's involved
in state government,
somebody's got to know it.
Well, I'll put out a few
feelers. I'll stay in touch.
Right.
Jury selection continues
in the Emerson/Coolidge
murder case
with a trial expected
to begin on Monday.
I'm Nelson White,
and we'll look for you
at our 6:00 news roundup
this evening.
And you're clear.
Very nice, Mr. White, sir.
I'll take that for you.
Excuse me, Mr. White.
If you want to talk to
me, use a subpoena.
Oh, no, we don't wanna do that.
Well, maybe we do.
I mean, you've become such
an important figure in this case.
I can't imagine why.
Because of your affair
with Linda Coolidge.
Who told you that?
I'm sure you must
recognize this.
Don't you?
Linda's diary.
She wrote about me in there?
Mr. White, now, how's
it gonna look to people
if they found out you
had an affair with her
and then she broke it off,
and then she tried to take
over your news program
and get you fired.
I mean, it looks like you
have a motive for murder.
Now, seriously,
wouldn't you really
rather talk to me, hm?
Look, it took me a
while to figure out
what a... user she was.
But she didn't break up with me.
I'm the one who called it off,
when I found out
she was after my job.
Isn't that in there too?
No.
It's not?
No, it's not.
Well, thanks for your time.
Oh,
here's the subpoena,
just in case.
What did you find
when you arrived
at the decedent's apartment?
Miss Coolidge was lying
on the living room floor
bleeding from a chest wound.
Mm-hm. Did you
summon medical help?
The security guard
at the apartment complex
had already done that.
The paramedics
arrived shortly after I did.
They determined she was dead.
Mm-hm.
I show you People's Exhibit 2...
and ask if you recognize it.
Yes, that's a .38
caliber revolver.
Was a ballistics test
performed on this revolver?
Yes, it was.
What was the
result of that test?
Ballistics tests
determined that the bullet
removed from Miss Coolidge's
chest was fired from that gun.
Where was this gun found?
On the floorboard
of a rented car
parked outside of the
apartment complex.
To whom was this
car rented at the time?
Mr. Steve Emerson.
Thank you.
No further questions.
Your witness.
No questions, Your Honor.
Mr. McCall.
Oh, hello. What is it?
You've been quite a
help to Steve Emerson.
We're all very grateful.
Oh, well, I'm sure he'd
do the same for me.
No, really. You've
gone out of your way.
Well, uh, no, it
was nothing, really.
Listen, would you excuse me?
'Cause, uh, I have some
people waiting for me.
But as helpful as
you've been to Steve,
I can never seem to
pinpoint you for an interview.
Well, that is
because, young lady,
I have nothing to add
that would be very useful,
I'm afraid.
Now, if you will excuse me,
I am running a bit late.
Gee, you could always
find time for Linda Coolidge
in the middle of the
afternoon, couldn't you.
Just what the hell is
that supposed to mean?
This makes for
very good reading.
Hm.
All right, why don't
you just tell me
what it is you want from me, hm?
I'm just curious.
When Linda Coolidge
broke off your affair,
were you so angry
that you murdered her?
She wasn't worth it.
Although I did, uh...
Yeah, I threw away a
15-year marriage for her.
And I suppose there
was a moment when I...
I would have loved
to have killed her.
But I, uh...
Well, I guess I
just wasn't up to it.
Satisfied?
Pretty much.
But here's a
subpoena, just in case.
Now, Mrs. Harris,
you testified that you saw
Steve Emerson, the defendant,
enter Linda Coolidge's apartment
at exactly 9:30
p.m., is that correct?
Yes, sir, it is.
How did you fix
on that exact time?
There's a clock on
top of my television set.
Oh, I see. I see.
You were looking at TV,
and when the program was
over you took your dog for a walk,
is that correct?
Yes, it is.
Well, that certainly explains
why you're so precise
as to the time. Hm.
Uh, now, Mrs.
Harris, you testified
that before the
gunshot, at 10:15,
you heard Steve Emerson
and Linda Coolidge arguing.
That's right.
Could you make out
what they were saying?
Well, I couldn't make it
out, but it sounded angry.
Well, how do you know it
was Steve Emerson's voice?
Well, I've been watching
him on television for years.
I recognized it.
Mrs. Harris, isn't it true
that you fixed the
time of the gunshot
because you were looking at TV
and you saw that clock
you were talking about?
Yes.
Mrs. Harris,
how can you be looking
at and listening to TV,
and identify Steve
Emerson's voice
through the apartment wall?
I heard him.
I suppose you can
assume it was his voice,
since you saw him
enter the apartment,
45 minutes earlier.
That's right.
Thank you, Mrs. Harris.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
You may be excused.
Do you wanna tell me
why you let her off so easy?
I made my point.
If I had kept after
her, she'd have dug in
and stuck to her story
come hell or high water.
Look like I was harassing
a nice, sweet lady.
Could you tell me if she
sublet her apartment to anyone?
No. No, I wouldn't
be interested.
Thank you.
Where have you been?
Oh, Corporations Commission.
How did it go today
with the flashing that
phony diary around?
Not great.
Both McCall and White
thought it was the real thing.
So I guess that eliminates them.
Maybe I should
try it on Lockwood.
The boyfriend? Why?
Well, if he and Linda were to be
married at the end of the month,
why would she make
plans to sublet her apartment
and then go to New York?
Maybe Mr. Lockwood
was gonna go with her.
And walk away from his business?
Maybe. And maybe not.
So where you going now?
I'm gonna go try
this on Lockwood.
Let me go with you.
No way, Tyler.
This one's on me.
Hm.
So at no time did you
ever see Mr. Emerson
leave the building?
Uh, no, I did not.
And from the position
of your desk in the lobby,
he would have
had to pass by you.
That's right.
And you never left your desk.
Uh, not until I got the
call about the gunshot.
Right.
Thank you.
No further questions.
Your witness.
Mr. Banning,
how does a person gain
access to your building?
Uh, either through
the front entrance
or, if they have a key,
the garage elevator.
All right. Who has these keys?
The tenants.
Do you know how many keys
were issued to Linda Coolidge?
Two, I believe.
Heh. Thank you, Mr. Banning.
Oh, by the way,
are you familiar with
the National Informer?
Am I what?
Have you ever read
the National Informer?
Uh... Oh...
Well, ye... Yes.
Isn't it true that reporters
and photographers
were at the entrance
to your building
shortly after
Mr. Emerson arrived?
Uh, I believe so, yes.
Now, Mr. Banning,
it's my understanding
that, uh, publications,
ahem, like the Informer,
ones that deal in
gossip and such,
frequently pay
people to alert them
as to the comings and
goings of celebrities.
Now, that's always
seemed curious to me,
that they got there so soon
after Mr. Emerson arrived.
How do you suppose
they knew he was there?
I-I don't know.
I want you to
think very carefully
before you answer
this next question.
Did you call them the
night of the murder?
No.
Have you ever received money
from the National Informer?
No.
Sir, would you stand?
Do you recognize that gentleman
as Mr. J.L. Dupree of
the National Informer?
Uh, no.
Now, the National Informer
keeps very careful records
of all cash disbursements.
Before I call
Mr. Dupree to the stand,
I want to give you
the opportunity
to reconsider your testimony.
And remember, you're under oath.
Did you call them the
night of the murder?
Did you call 'em?
Well...
Yes. And when they arrived,
you met them at
the front entrance,
talked with them and
they gave you money.
Isn't that correct?
Yes. And while you were absent
from your desk,
Mr. Emerson could have
come down to the lobby,
seen them at the entrance,
gone out a side
door. Isn't that so?
I was only gone a moment.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
You can step down.
Court will recess until 9
a.m. tomorrow morning.
Thanks for stopping by, O.J.
This is Steve Emerson.
Oh, big fan of yours.
Hi, how are you?
Anyway, thanks for stopping by.
Go ahead and order
that field corn for me,
and I'll settle up next week.
Sure thing. Deal.
Field corn, huh?
I didn't say he was from
the National Informer.
I just asked him if
he recognized him
from the National Informer.
Congratulations, Matlock.
You made quite a run at
discrediting Mrs. Harris,
hearing Emerson, totally
impeached Banning.
Very slick stuff.
Coming from you that's
quite a compliment.
But I'll tell you something.
I really don't see
how you're going to get around
not having a convincing alibi.
And that gun in the car.
See you tomorrow.
What are we gonna do about that?
Oh, we might have a
few surprises left in us.
I hope so.
- Where's Charlene?
- I don't know. Why?
My unimpeachable sources
say the mob is funding a
big coastal resort project
currently under review by the
Land Development Commission.
Anybody on the
commission we know?
Ah, Mr. Lockwood.
Mr. Lockwood is a
dollar-a-year man for the state.
Head of the Land
Development Commission.
All right. Not so all right.
Last time I talked to Charlene,
she was on her way out there
to try that diary on Lockwood.
I don't know about you,
but I'm going home now.
He knows I'm still waiting.
He knows.
Well, thanks.
Bye.
Mr. Lockwood, I really
do have to talk to you.
What do you want?
Did you have a serious
falling out with Linda Coolidge?
I really don't know
what you're talking about.
She made an entry
in her diary about you
that I really don't understand.
Her what?
Her diary. This.
What is that?
You don't recognize her diary?
What kind of a game
are you playing?
We will see you in
court, Mr. Lockwood.
Matlock and Matlock.
At the sound of the tone,
please leave your
name and number.
Ben, hi. Uh, it... It's me.
It's about 8:15 tonight.
Well, Lockwood's our man.
He, um... He recognized that
the diary was a phony write-off.
Anyway, he must
have been the one
that took it from
Linda's apartment.
I'm gonna go check
out his office to s...
Are you all right?
He did it, Ben. He killed her.
What are you people
doing in my plant?
You sure you're all right? Yeah.
It would seem to me
you're trespassing.
I think you'd better leave.
Let's go.
I'll be with you in a minute.
You're all right?
Yeah.
Would you have risked your
neck like that for any other client?
Oh, Dad, don't start
on me. Not now.
I know it's none of my business,
and he's a nice
enough guy, I guess,
but he's here now
because he has to be.
If he acquitted, he's going
to go back to his own life.
I said my piece, and I
won't mention it again.
I promise.
I'm sure glad you're all right.
Okay.
Get some rest. We got a
lot of work to do tomorrow.
I wanna nail Lockwood to
the side of the barn so bad,
I can taste it.
But we don't have anything.
Nothing at all.
Well, Lockwood had
motive and access.
So did Steve.
Whose side are you on?
Right now I'm on the jury.
And if we put
this solid citizen,
the grieved fiancé, on the stand
and grill him over the hot coals
without so much
as a workable theory
of how he might
have killed this woman,
then I'm gonna say let's convict
Steve Emerson and go home.
I wanna put Paul
Lockwood on the stand,
but we don't have a
dime's worth of anything.
Well, he was
supposed to have been
at this fundraiser at
the Mayfair all evening.
How do we get around
that? Tyler's down there now
trying to find anybody who
saw him leave before 10:15.
Charlene said there was
some TV news footage
taken outside the
apartment building that night.
It's at the station.
Can we look at it?
I'm sure McCall would cooperate.
Anything to avoid
his day in court.
Yo, folks, what do we
got on the tube, here?
Uh, rough news footage
from the night of the murder.
Fifteenth time.
What did you find
out at the hotel?
None of the staff saw him leave.
That means we have to go
through the entire guest list.
That could take weeks.
Let's see it again.
Ready?
Hold it right there.
Now, you see the exit sign
behind Lockwood, there?
Maybe some of the people there
saw him slip out
or come back in.
No, no, we don't know
who all those people are.
Yeah.
Let me see all
this just once more.
I got a feeling there's
something we're overlooking.
One more time, real quick.
All right, hold that one.
Now that one.
Now, here.
Of course.
It was there all the time.
All right.
Let's do put
Mr. Lockwood on the stand.
Mr. Lockwood, you are chairman
of the Land Development
Commission, is that correct?
Yes, it is.
Is there currently
under deliberation,
uh, a petition to grant
a zoning variance
to something called the Georgia
Coastal Development Company?
Yes, there is.
Why do they want the variance?
This group of developers
is hoping to build a resort
on what has been restricted
beachfront property.
Are you aware
that the Georgia Coastal
Development Company
is a subsidiary of American
Unified Finance Corporation?
I didn't bring documentation
regarding these
matters with me...
Your Honor, I object on
the grounds of relevancy.
Ahem, Your Honor, I
will prove the relevancy
with this line of questioning.
Overruled.
Thank you.
Now, I have here a list
of the board of directors
of American Unified.
Are you aware that at least
four of these board members
are currently under
federal indictment
for income tax evasion?
No, I am not.
And do you realize
that those same men
have long criminal records?
No.
Now, Mr. Lockwood,
you had a close,
personal relationship
with Linda Coolidge,
is that correct?
We were to be married.
Did you have a key
to her apartment?
Yes, I did.
Now, Mr. Lockwood,
the night of the murder
you were at a fundraising
dinner downtown.
Yes.
Were you there all evening?
I left when I received word
that Linda had been shot.
I was asked to
identify the body.
But you didn't
leave before that?
No.
Your Honor,
we have some
audio-visual material
that's pertinent
to this witness.
May we have permission
to bring it into the court?
Your Honor, this
entire line of questioning
is totally irrelevant.
I will demonstrate the
relevancy with the demonstration.
Overruled.
This'll just take a minute.
Now, on this first screen,
we're gonna see news footage
taken at the fundraising dinner.
Hold it right there.
And on the second screen,
we'll see more news footage
in front of the
decedent's apartment
the night of the murder.
Okay... hold it right there.
See? There he is.
Going in to identify the body.
On the third screen,
more news footage
of Mr. Lockwood
coming out later, after
identifying the body.
Freeze it, Tyler.
Your Honor, I-I still fail
to see the
relevance of all this.
Counsel for the defense
is indulging in his
well-known habit
of turning a courtroom
into a sideshow.
Your Honor, this is
crucial to our defense.
If you'll bear with me
a few more minutes.
Overruled.
Mr. Lockwood,
isn't it true that you slipped
out of that banquet unseen?
No.
And didn't you go to
Linda Coolidge's apartment,
where you argued with her
over exposing your connection
to organized crime through
a proposed news story
with Steve Emerson? No.
Didn't you struggle
with her and kill her?
Absolutely not.
But Mr. Lockwood,
you see, here at the banquet
you were wearing a name tag
like the other guests.
When you went to her
apartment to identify the body,
you were not wearing a name tag.
However, when
you came out again,
you were wearing
a name tag again.
You know what I think?
I think during the
struggle with her,
before you killed her,
that name tag
came off your suit.
And when you came
back, as you say,
to identify the body,
you found that name
tag and put it back,
which is why you are
wearing it right there.
I'm not on trial here.
You got that part right.
I don't have to prove
your guilt here and now.
I leave that in the skillful
hands of the prosecution.
They'll find somebody who
saw you leave that dinner.
They may even find somebody
who saw you near Emerson's car
when you put the gun there.
I just have to show this jury
that there's more than
a reasonable doubt
that Steve Emerson
committed this crime.
And I suppose we have
you to thank for that.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
We find the
defendant not guilty.
Congratulations, Mr. Emerson.
Mr. Matlock.
Excuse me.
Congratulations, Mr. Emerson.
Can we have a statement?
This is obviously
a great day for me
and for the press in general.
I mean, we were
right down to the wire,
but we pulled it out.
You...? You have any plans now?
All I wanna do right now is I
want to get back to New York,
and I wanna get back to work.
Excuse me, miss.
You don't think this
will have any effect
on your returning to your show?
- I hope not.
What about the case? Do you
think Matlock did a good job?
- Yes, I do.
- What about rumors
of you and Matlock's daughter?
No comment.
Tyler, you coming?
Yo.
Well, this probably
won't be on TV tomorrow,
but I know what a great
job the both of you did,
so I'm taking you to dinner.
All right. Where are we going?
Santino's. Santino's?
That's some kind of
pickup joint, ain't it?
No, it's where we
yuppies go to unwind.
Yeah, haven't you ever
seen a beer commercial?
www.tvsubtitles.net